DIPANKAR DUTTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+91888204060

dutta.dipankar08@gmail.com

Collindale, London, UK Q

www.linkedin.com/in/dipankar08 in

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

With 7+ years of strong technical experience in delivering high availability, scalable, enterprise class products. I have shipped multiple successfully products/featurs at Facebook(London infra), Microsoft (Office Android & Excel Mac), Amazon (Web backends) and Citrix (OpenStack and Cloud).

EDUCATION Facebook

M.Tech, CSE IIT Roorkee, INDIA 2009 - 2011

> B.Tech, CSE HIT, Haldia 2005 - 2009

EXPERIENCE

Facebook Inc • 2017 - Present

Software Engineer • Collobation infra • London UK

- Shipped Camera control for Messenger within 2 mohths
- Shiped WorkVc for new consumer h/w device by facebook.
- Owning RTC over VC endpoints for android client (workchat)
- Shiped more than 2Lac Significant Line of code in last month.

Microsoft Devlopment Center • 2014 - 2017

Software Engineer, Hyderabad India

- Shipped CCP feature for WXP android platform.
- Shipped Multiple App Activation(App Boot) in shared infra which eable 3 major feature in app level.
- Owned Apphost/Fast mode and other ACXE compoent for Office
- Shiped SDM and import text feature for excel in Mac platform.

SKILL

C, C++, Java, Python

Experinced Android Dev

Experinced Infra/backend Devloper

Software architect with applied software patterns

Git, Hg, Automation

Amazon Devlopment Center • 2012 - 2014

Software Engineer, Bangalore, IN

- Migrated checkout pipeline to Webstore for Javari and BuyVIP to leverage the func like adding Solo/MasterCard credit card and multiple promotions.
- Achieved more than 50% latency reduction in UK,DE,JP, FR locale.
- Shiped responsive Design for checkout pipeline and Sign-in pages using media queries to support mobile,tablet and Desktop.
- OnCall Duty whre i have solved 33+ production tickets and fixed 190+ internal bugs.

AWARDS

99.97% in GATE GATE, IITs 2009 College Topper HIT, Haldia 2009

Citrix R&D • July,2011 - June, 2012

Software Engineer, Bangalore, IN

- Contributed to OpenStack/CloudStack initiative by Citrix.
- Worked on the major service components which is required for setting up a cloud like Nova, Keystone integration, LBaaS and Openstack Dashboard Integration
- Shipped KeyStone Auth Mechanism and API, which allow diffeent user/tanent to interect with service endpoint.

